Today is a great day for all of us
今天對我們是大日子
that we are celebrating Navaratri today
我們今天慶祝女神拉特利節
and all of us are meeting after such a long time of My tour.
在我長時間的旅程後 與大家 會面
When in Italy I said that
在意大利 我說
England is the heart of the universe,
英國是宇宙的心臟
they would not accept it.
他們不接受這種說法
They were very shocked at this statement.
對這句話很震驚
They couldn't believe that England could be the heart of the universe.
他們不能相信英國是宇宙的心臟
One of the reasons was that they felt that
其中一個原因是他們感到
that the English people were invaded once by Romans,
羅馬人曾經侵略英國
and Romans at that time also had felt
那時候的羅馬人也感到
that English were very bumptious people.
英國人很傲慢自大
They would not even accept the defeat
他們甚至不能接受被擊敗
with the grace of a person who is lost.
缺乏戰敗者應有的風度
Even if they were lost, they used to be bumptious.
即使他們失敗了 卻仍傲慢自大
So they could not believe how could it be
所以他們不能相信
that the English is the heart of the universe.
英國怎會是宇宙的心臟
If this is the heart, what's the situation of the universe?
若英國是心臟 宇宙會處於怎樣 的境況
And then they described to Me at length the bumptiousness of the English,
接著他們很詳盡的描述英國人的 傲慢
and then I felt I have known something like that Myself.
令我感到好像我是知道英國人的
Now, when we are celebrating the greatest of greatest this Navaratri,
現在 當你們慶祝這個偉大中 最偉大的女神拉特利節
there must be something special about it,
它必定有些特別之處
that we have to cleanse this heart completely,
我們要完整地潔淨這顆心
fully
完全的
and make it so pure that it purifies all the blood
令它那麽純潔 以至它能潔淨
that passes through the whole of the body.
流通於整個身體的血液
So the cells of this heart,
所以構成這個重要器官的心臟 細胞
has to be the best, because the cells of the heart
要是最好的 因為人體裡
within a human body are the best cells,
最好的細胞是心臟細胞
the highest quality, the most sensitive.
它質素最佳 最敏銳
And it's the heart that expresses the Anahata,
是這顆心表達純粹的喜樂Anahata
the sound that is without percussion.
那聲音不含任何碰撞
While we find
我們發現
that there are some people of caliber, there are,
有些人很有能力
but others talk more, show off more,
有些人卻只說話 只炫燿
and do not have the caliber.
卻沒有能力
Now to achieve that caliber should be possible
擁有這份能力是有可能的
because you are born on the special land of England.
因為你是出生在英國這片特別的 土地上
That possibility must be built within you.
這份可能要在你內在建構
But then what is lacking?
那麽還缺少什麽
Why is it, that with all the possibility,
為何會這樣 在有各種發展潛力
with all the great background,
各種了不起的背景
with all the merits to be here,
各種優勢下
why is it we find
在這裡 我們發覺
that Sahaja yogis for years together do not come up to many others.
為何這麽多年 霎哈嘉瑜伽士 的人數還未能大量增加
What is the reason?
什麽原因
Heart, if you see, has a pulse rate
心臟 若你看到 有心跳率
and it moves with a certain sound,
跳動時有某種聲音
and you can even get it on to a graph
你甚至能把這些頻率畫成圖表
and it is so systematic,
它是很有系統
it is so regularized, it is so disciplined,
很有規則 很有紀律
that even a slightest murmur,
即使很微細的雜音
or slightest change shows on the graph.
或微細的改變也能在圖表裡顯示
Is a very sensitive thing.
它是很敏銳的
And that is what is lacking here, is that discipline of the heart.
這裡就是缺少了心臟的規律
It's an erratic, funny heart
這裡是不規則
which swells up in ego.
自我膨脹奇怪的心臟
And whatever one may talk,
不管你說什麽
this is another reading people have,
都有人有另一種解讀
that whatever you may tell them, that time seriously they listen to you
不管你告訴他們什麽 這一刻 他們會認真的聽你說
and second moment it has no effect on them.
下一刻你的話對他們就沒有任何 效用了
So this is another thing we should see that if it is within us,
這是另一樣我們要觀察的 自己 內裡是否有此情況
let us understand that what we lack is disciplining.
讓我們明白 我們缺少的是紀律
And that disciplining has to come, otherwise our caliber cannot improve.
要有紀律 不然我們的能力不能 改善
But for all that, I think what we should have is innate intelligence.
但對你們全部人 我想我們要有 的是天生的才智
No education, innate intelligence.
不是教育 是天生的才智
Innate intelligence to understand that our caliber has to improve.
天生的才智去明白我們的能力要 改善
Now here pulsates the Spirit,
現在這裡 靈在脈動
the Spirit and not the Power.
是靈而不是那力量
The witness,
旁觀者
the one that watches,
靜觀的人
that is the reflection of God,
這是神的反映
who is the Spectator of the work of the Devi.
祂是看著女神工作的觀眾
Actually what happens
實際發生的是
that without rising up to that status
在還沒有提昇到這個層次下
if we also say,
若我們仍說
"All right, we are also watching because we are the Spirit,"
好吧 我們也在觀看 因為我們 是靈
then we do not achieve that caliber.
那麽我們就是未有這份能力
And with all the blessings,
藉著所有福佑
like seven auras of the heart, we have got seven ashrams.
像心的七個氛圍 我們已取得 七所靜室
We do not understand that we all have to discipline ourselves.
我們不明白要律己
Only to take advantage
只是利用霎哈嘉瑜伽
or to be in the Sahaja Yoga
或只是在霎哈嘉瑜伽
to claim that you are a Sahaja Yogi,
就稱自己為霎哈嘉瑜伽士
is not a sign of being a cell of the heart.
這不是作為心臟細胞的徵兆
And warning has to be given now.
現在要提出警告
Very important is at this juncture
在這交接點 很重要
when Sahaja Yoga is now taking off, remember this,
霎哈嘉瑜伽現在要起飛 記著
the speed has been gained and it is taking off.
已夠速度 在起飛
Those who will be left behind, will be left behind.
那些仍留在後面的人會被遺 留下來
So don't get into bumptiousness.
所以不要自滿自大
First is your character, as everybody says,
首先是你的性格 就如每個人說
"They are very bumptious."
他們很傲慢自大
Try to be humble
要謙虛
and then understand that you have to be in the plane
要明白你要在飛機上
and not left behind on the grounds.
不要遺留在地面
It is moving fast.
它移動得很快速
Now the most fortunate thing is
現在 最幸運的是
that today is the Navaratri
今天是女神拉特利節
and that I should be in London
我應該在倫敦
and this Navaratri Puja should be performed here.
這個女神崇拜應在倫敦舉行
No other country is that privileged,
沒有其他國家有這份特權
because this is the highest puja,
因為這是你能出席最高的崇拜
the greatest ritual, which you can attend.
最偉大的儀式
So why do we do Navaratri?
那麽為何我們要做女神拉特利節 崇拜
In the heart, to do Navaratri is to accept
在心裡 做女神拉特利節崇拜
the powers of the Shakti,
是接受女神的力量
to realize the power
意識到每個輪穴都有它的力量
and that when they are enlightened
當輪穴得到開悟
how you can express all these powers
你怎樣表達你內在
of these nine chakras within ourselves;
這九個輪穴的力量
the seven chakras plus the heart and the moon makes it nine.
七個輪穴加心臟和月亮就成為九
But I would say that
我總是只說七個輪穴
seven of these and on top of that we should say two more centers,
除此之外 我們應說還有多兩個 能量中心
which Blake has described surprisingly as nine centers, clearly.
威廉布萊克很令人驚訝的曾經 清楚的描述九個能量中心
Just now I cannot talk of the higher two centers,
現在此刻 我不能談那兩個更高 的能量中心
but let us at least talk of the seven centers.
讓我們至少談七個能量中心
The power of these centers,
我們是否能在內裡 發展這些 能量中心的力量
How can you do it? You have no time.
你能怎樣做 你們沒時間
You are all busy people and bumptious.
你們全都很忙 都很自負
So now to develop these powers
要發展這些力量
we have to concentrate on these chakras.
我們要集中注意這些輪穴
Everywhere I went, I was surprised,
我到過的每一處 我都很驚訝
the questions they asked Me, the way they were.
他們問我的問題 他們的言行
Nobody talked about their family,house, jobs or
沒有人談自己的家庭、房子、 工作
any other nonsensical thing like
或其他像失業等等荒謬的事情
They just asked Me,
他們只問我
"Mother, how do we develop the power of this chakra,
母親 我們怎能發展這個輪穴的 力量
or that chakra or that chakra?"
或那個輪穴的力量
And I asked them, "How is it you are asking about a particular chakra?"
我問他們：你為何特別問這個 輪穴
They said, "Because we find this is missing in us,
他們說 因為我們發覺這是我們 缺少的
This is another negativity to make My throat all right.
這是另一種負面能量令我的喉嚨 妥當
Now for a realized soul
對有自覺的靈
there is no need for Me to discipline you or to tell you all these things,
我不需要管束你或告訴你這些 事情
because I hate to talk in this tone to you today.
因為我討厭今天以這種語氣與你 說話
But I have discovered, that if I do not warn you now,
但我發現 若我今天不警告你
tomorrow you will blame Me that I did not warn you.
明天你會責怪我沒有警告你
Take it as a serious warning.
把它視為嚴重的警告
Now after Realization
一旦你有自覺
there is no need for Me to discipline you at all,
我完全不用管束你
because you have got the light,
因為你已有光
you have known what is Realization,
已經知道什麽是自覺
you have known what it means to be realized,
亦知道得到自覺是什麽意思
and you have also known how much you have gained out of it,
你也知道自己從中有多少得益
how much your personality has improved.
性格有多少改善
But, there is something more that has to be done.
但你們仍要做多一點
Is to see for yourself,
就是要看看自己
if you have really disciplined yourself or not.
你是否真的好好管束自己
There is no need for any leader to tell you,
沒需要任何領袖告訴你
there is no need for any ashram fellow to tell you,
沒需要任何集體靜室的傢伙 告訴你
there is no need for anyone to tell you.
沒需要任何人告訴你
It is you, who is a realized soul,
是你 這個有自覺的靈告訴自己
you are your own master,
你是自己的導師
you are your own guru. Imagine you are all gurus,
自己的導師 試想像你們全都是 導師
great gurus and satgurus, respected saints
偉大的導師 真正的導師 受 尊重的聖人
where all the angels have to shower you with flowers.
所有的天使都要向你們灑下花朵
Think of it.
想想這些事情
And here you are bumptiously giving lectures, talking bumptiously.
然而在這裡 你卻在傲慢演講 大言不慚
Very embarrassing even for the deities.
即使神祇也感到很尷尬
They don't know what to do, whether to garland you or to shut your mouth.
他們不知道該怎麽辦 是為你 獻上花環還是要你閉嘴
Here you are who have been,
在這裡 你就是這樣
here you are in such a great position
你處於這樣了不起的位置
that you have got Realization.
你已有自覺
That only thing you have to accept
你唯一要接受的是
the beauty of this great yoga,
這偉大瑜伽的美麗
that you just enlighten your own powers,
你開悟了自己的力量
which are on these seven chakras.
這些力量就在七個輪穴裡
Now let us see the first chakra, belongs to the power of Gauri,
現在讓我們看看第一個輪穴 它 屬於哥維(Gauri)的力量
the power of the Mother of Shri Ganesh.
格涅沙母親的力量
Gauri's power.
哥維的力量
Tremendous they are, aren't they?
他們很巨大 對嗎
Because of Her power you have got your Realization.
因為祂的力量 你得到自覺
Now what have we done
那麽我們自己做了什么
to enshrine that power within ourselves?
去莊嚴神聖地承載這份內在的 力量
Today, if it is the first day of Navaratri,
若今天是女神拉特利節的第一天
let us see what have we done?
讓我們看看我們做了什麽
Have we been able to develop our innocence within ourselves?
我們是否已發展內在的純真
When people talk, they are so sharp.
人們的說話是那麽尖酸刻薄
How can you be sharp, if you are innocent?
若你是純真的 又怎會說話刻薄
They are so bumptious.
他們是那麽自大
How can you be that, if you are innocent?
若你是純真的 又怎會自大
People play games.
人們玩把戲
How can you do that, if you are innocent?
若你是純真的 又怎會玩把戲
Harm each other.
互相傷害
How can it be, if you are innocent?
若你是純真的 怎能這樣
So first of all you have to see yourself,
所以首先你要看看自己
that the power of innocence, if it has to live,
純真的力量 若要擁有純真
all the rest of the nonsense has to go away.
其餘的荒謬事物必須離去
If you want to have the innocence,
若你想有純真
all that is anti-innocence has to be dropped out.
要拋掉所有反純真的事物
I can understand about people, who are ignorant,
我能明白人 誰是無明的
who have ignorance.
誰有無明
Then in ignorance, of course how will they talk of innocence.
在無明中 他們理所當然怎會談 純真
But you are not ignorant people. You are knowledgeable,
但你不是無明的人 你知識豐富
you've got your enlightenment.
因為你已經開悟了
And the power of innocence is so great.
純真的力量是那麽巨大
It makes you absolutely fearless, not bumptious, but fearless.
令你無畏無懼 并非傲慢自大 而是無畏無懼
And the greatest thing of innocence is that you are respectful.
純真最了不起的特性是你變得 充滿尊重
The sense of respect,
若你內在沒有發展尊重的意識
if you cannot develop the sense of respect for other Sahaja Yogis,
若你不能發展對其他霎哈嘉瑜 伽士
for other people, for the ashrams, for the discipline
對其他人 對集體靜室 對紀律
and your own self-respect,
對自己自尊的尊重意識
then it is of no use, even talking of Sahaja Yoga,
那麽 即使談霎哈嘉瑜伽也毫無 用處
because that is the very beginning of it.
因為一切始於尊重
First you do not respect, all right, you are bumptious, all right,
首先 你不尊重人 好吧 你 自負, 好吧
you are in a big fool's paradise, as they call it,
你在他們稱呼的大笨蛋天堂
riding a fast horse,
騎著一匹快馬
all that is there is all right, is forgiven.
在那裡 一切還可以 你會被 寛恕
But once you have seen the light,
但一旦你看到光
you must try to get rid of all the snakes
你必須把手上拿著的蛇拋掉
Is a simple thing.
就是這樣簡單
In your childlike nature only,
你要有像孩子般的品質
you can receive the blessings of Gauri, otherwise you cannot.
才能接受哥維的祝福 不然你 不能
You have to be really childlike,
你真的要像孩子
otherwise it is absolutely useless, no use telling you anything,
不然是完全沒用 告訴你什麽也 沒用
because you think you're too clever.
因為你以為自己太聰明
To such a person, who thinks he is too clever,
對這樣的人 以為自己很聰明 的人
what's the use of talking to such a person,
與他們說話有什麽用呢
because he already knows everything.
因為他已經知道一切
So the first power when you develop,
當你發展第一個力量
you must learn to sit on the Mother Earth, first of all.
你必須學習坐在大地之母上
You must respect the Mother Earth,
首先 你要尊重大地之母
because the first chakra is made out of the Mother Earth.
因為第一個輪穴是從大地之母 創造而來
Try to be more settled down with yourself on Mother Earth.
嘗試讓自己更能在大地之母上 安頓下來
And the respect.
還有那份尊重
See the trees when they get their flowers,
看看樹木 當它們長出花朵
they are not so respectful,
並不怎樣恭敬
but when they are laden by the fruits,
但當它們負滿果實
they bow down to Mother Earth.
就會向大地之母躬身彎下
In the same way when you have got the fruits of Sahaja Yoga,
同樣 當你得到霎哈嘉瑜伽的 果實
you all must bow down.
你們全都要躬身彎下
And innocence has a special capacity
純真有份特別的能耐
to make a person extremely peaceful,
能令人極之平和
extremely peaceful.
極之平和
All the anger, temper, violence -
所有憤怒、脾氣、暴力
if a person doesn't have innocence,
若人沒有純真
it cannot come in you,
就沒有平和
because a person who is not innocent
因為不純真的人
is either sly or aggressive.
不是狡猾就是專橫
He cannot have peace within his heart.
他內心沒有平和
But a innocent person is not bothered, innocently he lives,
純真的人就不受打擾 他活得很 純真
he enjoys everything in complete peace and harmony.
他以完全平和諧協享受一切
But this violence comes when a person becomes clever.
當人變得聰明 這種暴力就會 出現
He thinks, "I am so clever, the another one is so stupid,
他以為 我這麽聰明 另一個人 那麽愚蠢
I have a right to shout at that person."
我有權向這個人呼喝
And the one who is not innocent is never wise.
不純真的人永遠沒有智慧
He may be to look at look sharp, but he is not wise.
他或許看來很敏銳 但卻沒有 智慧
Wisdom comes only with innocence.
有純真才有智慧
And how much wisdom have you gathered?
你們收集了多少智慧
That is what one has to see.
你們要看清這點
When your power
當你的純真力量增加
of innocence increases, wisdom is apparent.
智慧就很明顯
People say, "That fellow is very wise."
人們說 這傢伙很有智慧
For example if somebody is crying about his wife,
例如 有人為他的妻子哭泣
a wise person will say, "Oh, Baba,
有智慧的人會說 噢！巴巴
just look at this, still busy with his wife."
你看看他 仍為他的妻子而忙碌
Another one is crying about his house or something.
另一個人為他的房子或什麽哭泣
He will say, "Oh, look at this one, still busy with the house."
他會說 噢！看這個人 仍為他 的房子忙碌
There is no end to it.
沒完沒了
I've known people who get so swollen up
我知道有些人很驕傲自滿
that they think they must give a big lecture for one hour,
他們以為自己必須為霎哈嘉瑜伽 演講一小時
Unless and until they have given one hour lecture,
除非他們已完成一小時演講
they do not think their ego has manifested itself fully.
他們不認為自己的自我能完全 彰顯
But a wise person,
但有智慧的人
he doesn't have to talk or speak or do anything.
他不用說話 不用做什麽
He impresses his silence,
他的沈默、他的智慧
his wisdom on others much more easily.
更容易令人刮目相看
That is what we have to see,
我們就是要看到這樣
have we been able to discipline ourselves?
我們是否能管束自己
Because our growth is very much in the beginning of it.
因為我們的成長仍然是在起步 階段
We have to grow quite a lot
我們仍要成長很多
And people don't understand this point
人們不明白這點
in an atmosphere of egoistical temperament
在自我的氛圍下
that you have to grow, you have not yet grown.
我們要成長 我們仍未成長
You have to grow a lot.
仍要成長很多
And when you grow
當你成長
you find this wisdom really fragrant with compassion.
你會發現 這份智慧真的散發 慈悲的芬芳
Your wisdom is fragrant with compassion.
你的智慧充滿慈悲的芬芳
Such beautiful compassion
這份漂亮的慈悲
can emit through your being,
能散發穿透你的存在體
that anybody who comes in contact with you,
任何與你接觸的人
will feel your auspiciousness.
都能感到你的吉祥
to your Self Realization and to your Self.
尊重你的自覺 尊重你的真我
That is the first thing you have to do, is to meditate.
你首先要做的 就是靜坐
Somebody sent Me a letter and I saw the vibrations were horrid.
有人寄信給我 我看到很可怕的 生命能量
I said, "What's the matter with this gentleman?
我說 這個男士怎麽了
His vibrations are so horrid, what is he doing?"
他的生命能量很差 他在做什麽
Then I found out that he says he doesn't need any meditation.
接著我發現 他說他不用靜坐
He has already reached the fourteenth heaven,
他已經到達第十四重天
so he doesn't need any meditation, doesn't have to do any meditation.
所以他不用靜坐 不用任何靜坐
Is easy to explain, but whom are you explaining?
這很容易解釋 但你在向誰解釋
You have to explain to yourself,
你要向自己解釋
only yourself, nobody else wants your explanation.
只向自己 沒有人要你的解釋
It's like missing the plane.
就像你錯失飛機
When you miss the plane
當你錯失了飛機
whom are you going to explain, the plane has left.
你向誰解釋飛機走了
So then you have to explain yourself only.
你只要向自己解釋
You will tell the air, or to the gangway,
你會告訴空氣 或告訴跳板
or anything that, "Oh baba, it happened like that,
或任何東西 噢 巴巴 事情就 是這樣發生了
there was this thing, I had no time, there was a jam, this, that."
就是這樣 我沒時間 交通擠塞 這樣那樣
But the plane is gone.
飛機已經飛走了
Whom are you explaining?
你在向誰解釋
So everyone should meditate every day.
每個人都要每天靜坐
That is a very important thing,
這是很重要的事情
which people are doing in all the countries where I am not.
每個國家的人都在做 我因此 不用為他們靜坐
Because I am in England, people take Me for granted.
因為我在英國 人們視我為理所 當然
"Mother is doing everything."
母親做一切
So I get up at 4 o'clock, take My bath, meditate for you all.
所以我四時起床 沐浴 為你們 全部人靜坐
I better start doing that again.
我最好再這樣做
Otherwise you have no time to meditate.
不然你沒有時間靜坐
So at least let Me meditate for your sake.
至少讓我因為你們而靜坐
So everyone must today promise to Me
每個人今天要向我承諾
that they will meditate every day.
你們會每天靜坐
Get up in the morning!
早上起床
"We can't get up in the morning."
我們不能早起
The whole world can get up, why not the English?
整個世界都能起床 為何英國 不能
But when it was the war of Waterloo,
在滑鐵盧戰爭時
they were the first to arrive there.
他們是第一個到達戰場
They won the war because they were so punctual.
贏得戰爭 因為他們是那麽準時
What has happened to their punctuality today?
今天 就準時而言 他們發生了 什麽
We are not drinking, we do not have hangovers,
我們沒有喝酒 沒有宿醉
we don't sleep late,
並不遲睡
so why shouldn't we decide today
所以為何我們今天不作決定
that, "Every morning I'll get up and do my meditation.
我每天早上起來靜坐
And while meditating I must concentrate on myself and not on others.
在靜坐中 我要集中精神在自己 身上 而不是別人
And see for myself what is catching,
看看自己有什麽阻塞
where am I catching, which chakra I am catching,
那裡有阻塞 那個輪穴有阻塞
what have I to do?"
我該做些什麽
So on this day of Navaratri,
在女神拉特利節的日子
today as the first day,
今天是第一天
the Gauri's power must be enlightened within us, and they must express.
必須開悟我們內在的哥維力量 它們必須彰顯
And they are tremendous. I cannot describe them in one lecture.
它們是巨大的 我不能在一個 講話裡完全描述它們
Think of the Primordial Kundalini.
想想太初靈量
She acts in the Mother Earth,
她在大地之母起作用
She acts in the universe,
在宇宙起作用
She acts in the animals,
在動物起作用
She acts in the matter,
在物質起作用
She acts in the human beings,
在人類起作用
and now She acts in you.
現在祂在你身上起作用
She is the One who decides
是祂決定
the face and the figure that you are going to have.
你有怎樣的面容 怎樣的身材
She is the One who decides what child you should have.
是祂決定你該有怎樣的孩子
She is the One
是祂
who gives you the particular type of a child that you need.
給你需要的特別類型的孩子
She is the One who has got you all these beautiful children.
是祂給你這些漂亮的孩子
She is the One
是祂
who has given you these sparkling faces and sparkling eyes.
給你這些閃亮的臉孔 閃亮的 眼睛
All this She has done for you,
全都是祂為你而做的
but what about the Power that you have within yourself.
但你內在的力量又怎樣
How much have you manifested that?
你彰顯了它多少
The Primordial is working very hard, no doubt.
太初在辛勤工作 毫無疑問
But what about you, the individuals,
你又怎樣
who have got their own Kundalini awakened?
你的靈量已經得到喚醒
How far you have opened Her out.
你開啓了祂多少
And what is Kundalini, is a simple thing as you know.
什麽是靈量 你也知道 很簡單
Is the true desire.
是真正的欲望
So true desire to perfect yourself, to grow yourself.
真正的欲望要令自己完美 令 自己成長
If it is really true desire, nothing else is important.
若這是真正的欲望 其他沒什麽 是重要的
All other desires are secondary and tertiary.
其他欲望都是次要和次次要的
The most important desire is to grow.
最重要的欲望是成長
And for whose advantage ? Is the advantage of yours
是為誰的好處 為你的好處
and in your advantage only, the advantage of the whole world rests.
在為你的好處下 整個世界的 好處都建基於此
Sahaja Yogis today represent the growth of this universe,
霎哈嘉瑜伽士代表宇宙的成長
the growth of the human race.
人類族群的成長
Do you follow this point
你有否領會到
that you are playing such an important role,
你在扮演這樣重要的角色
role at such a crucial time
在這個世界即將崩塌的關鍵時刻
when the world is about to collapse?
你是否知道自己扮演的角色
And you have great seers like William Blake,
你們擁有偉大的先知 像威廉 布萊克
you had such great people who have talked about this time.
你們擁有這種偉人 他曾談到 這個時刻
They have built it up, traditionally we have built up all this -
是他們建立的 傳統上 我們 已經建立這些
now, in England.
現在 在英國
The work of ages that has brought this England to gestate...
長年累月的工作成果帶英國到 現在這個階段
Now, do you realize
你是否意識到
that the position of English Sahaja Yogis is very important.
英國的霎哈嘉瑜伽士佔很重要的 位置
But lack of wisdom and bumptiousness
在缺少智慧 狂妄自大
without understanding your Self,
不理解真我下
how can you talk so loud?
你為何還高談闊論
How can you think of organizing everything
當你那麽虛弱 那麽自大 你還 想統籌一切
So today I am not going to take the count of the people,
所以今天我不準備計算
who meditate every day or not.
有多少人每天靜坐
But I can tell you this much,
我只能告訴你這麽多
next year those who do not meditate everyday,
明年那些沒有每天靜坐的人
you will not be here anymore.
不會再在這裡
Take it from Me.
是我說的
Is a fact.
這是事實
Every day you must meditate.
每天必需靜坐
Discipline yourself.
要好好管束自己
Now you have come to a new perspection, perspective.
現在你已經進入新的觀點角度
You have come to a new vision.
亦已到達新的遠景
Now when you see that vision, when you know the vision,
當你看到這個遠景 當你知道 這個遠景
you cannot just stand there.
你不能只站著
Get into it!
你要跳進去
Everyone says, Damle was saying too, everybody says
每個人都說 丹也這樣說 每個 人都說
that, "Mother you have spent so much time for these English.
母親 你為英國人花了這麽多 時間
Why so much time for them?"
為何要花那麽多時間在他們身上
Maybe you might be thinking that because you are very great,
或許你們以為自己很偉大
that's why I have to serve you people.
所以我要服務你們
Think the way you like.
你喜歡怎樣想就怎樣想吧
But the most important thing is that you are on the land of Heart,
最重要是你在心臟的土地上
and I have to cleanse you more, much more than others.
我要比其他人潔淨你更多更多
But it's just the other way round. Others are going so fast.
但情況卻相反 其他人走得很快
I am amazed, their vibrations, their sensitivity, their understanding.
我也很驚訝 他們的生命能量 他們的敏銳度 他們的理解力
And they have just mastered it; every one of them.
他們每一個人都能好好掌握它
Here, it is becoming a very centralized stuff
這裡 它變成自我中心的東西
and everybody doesn't want to understand Sahaja Yoga,
每個人都不想明白霎哈嘉瑜伽
but everyone wants to give a lecture.
但每個人都想演講
There is no respect for elders.
不尊敬年長的人
No respect who is older who is younger,
不管年長年幼都不尊重
and somebody who thinks that
有人以為
because they got Realization before others they are higher,
因為他們比其他人早有自覺 他們就更高
then remember one word of Christ, that, "First will be the last."
要記著基督說的一句話 最先會 是最後
So try to understand that it is you who has to grow,
要明白 是你要成長
it is you who has to manifest these powers.
是你要彰顯這些力量
Manifestation of the power,
力量的彰顯
I don't know how far you have understood.
我不知道你能明白多少
When a person who has Gauri's power,
當擁有哥維力量的人
as soon as he enters a hall or any place,
一旦進入會堂或任何地方
everybody's Kundalini rises, just to salute.
每個人的靈量都會昇起 向它 致敬
When you have Gauri's power
當你擁有哥維力量
then you stand out because you have that innocent,
你就很顯眼 因為你有這份純真
lustless, greedless, beautiful, sparkling eyes
全無慾念或貪婪 美麗閃亮的 眼睛
and wherever you turn your eyes,
不管你的眼睛投向那處
even one glance would raise the Kundalini, immediately.
即使只看一眼 靈量都會立即 昇起
People who suffer from cancer, suffer from this disease, that disease,
受癌病之苦 受這種那種疾病 之苦的人
all can be cured in no time
馬上就能痊癒
if you have developed only one power of Gauri.
你只要發展一種哥維的力量
All your problems can be solved.
你所有的問題都能得到解決
Negativity will go away
負面力量會離去
and you will become like a lotus.
你會變得像蓮花
Beautiful, fragrant,
漂亮 芳香
overpowering all kinds of negativity.
擊退各種負面能量
Here it is, "That fellow just touched me
這裡有人說 這傢伙剛碰了我 一下
and now I have become egoistical."
我就變得自我中心
If there is one fellow who is egoistical,
若有一個傢伙很自我
he just talks to another person, the person goes egoistical.
他只要與另一個人說話 那個人 就變得自我中心
I mean this is not the way to be sensitive.
我說敏感的意思不是要這樣
You have to be sensitive to God and not to bad things.
你要對神敏感  不是對壞事物 敏感
But we are more akin, more vulnerable to bad than to good.
但我們對壞事 比對好事 更為 親近和更易受傷害
So the power, the power of assimilation of good,
所以力量 吸收好事的力量
the power of emission of good,
散發好事的力量
all these powers are just in your complete reach.
所有這些力量完全在你能到達的 範圍
But all this should not become a praise
這一切不應變成稱讚
but should become a kind of a challenge,
而是變成一種挑戰
a kind of a beautiful curiosity
一種漂亮的好奇心
and an advancement for you.
能令你進步
But we are going down, I must tell you,
但我們卻在走下坡 我必須告訴 你
we are going down in England.
英國正在走下坡
Because we have some funny tags,
因為我們有一些奇怪的標籤
funny people who are all the time with tags.
奇怪的人常常有些標籤
Such people will have to be warned,
要警告這些人
and later on may be declared, as these people have decided,
遲一些可能要宣佈 這些人因 已經決定
should be declared as blacklisted.
要宣佈他們入黑名單
It's a very sad day today for Me
對我今天是很傷感的一天
and that is why the whole place is filled with -
這就是為何整個地方都充滿哀傷
I mean I had no mind to have the puja here,
我是說我沒心情在這裡做崇拜
because I am really very sad.
因為我真的很傷心
Because when I see the vibrations, when I see the way things are,
因為當我看到生命能量 當我看 到事情怎樣安排
people are just in a picnic way in England,
英國人只視為旅行
I feel so unhappy, you don't know.
我感到很不開心 你不會知道
I have always been extremely enamored,
我常常都極之迷惑
and I have already put up a big show of appreciating your efforts.
我已經演出了一齣很大的表演 讚賞你們的努力
But if you see in the substance of it;
若你看看它的本質
just see the substance, you watch within yourself.
只看本質 你們內觀自己
Each individual should see the substance that is within us.
每個人都要看看自己內在的本質
We are worried about a friend,
我們擔憂朋友
a fiancèe or a wife or a husband or this and that.
擔憂未婚夫或妻子或丈夫 擔憂 這擔憂那
That's not the caliber.
這就不是那需要的質素
The caliber is very low and is going down lower.
很低的質素 正在往下走
That's not a good thing, is not good.
這不是好事 不是好事
If My love and compassion is spoiling you, I better pull you out of it.
若我的愛和慈悲在縱容你 那麽 我最好還是把你拉出來
Because you are capable
因為你出生在
of your merits to be born in this country.
能發揮你的優點的英國
You are capable of very great heights.
你有能力到達很高的高度
I know that.
我知道你能
Of very great heights, which you can achieve.
你能到達很高的高度
But not by talking about it or thinking about it,
但不是只談論它 或想想它就能 到達
but by becoming that great power,
而是要成為這份偉大的力量
to become that power.
要成為這份力量
And see the collective blessings people have
看看人們擁有的集體祝福
and I was amazed when they told Me, they have got this blessing,
當他們告訴我 我很詫異
they have got that blessing.
他們已得到這份祝福
I mean unlimited blessings they have got.
我是說他們得到無限的祝福
And why can't we have that here?
那麽為何我們在這裡不能得到 同樣的祝福
What's the problem with us?
我們有什麽問題
If we are not collective, if there is a problem between ourselves,
若我們不合群集體 若我們之間 仍有問題
that means there is some sort of an ego still in-between
即是說仍有某種自我在我們之間
that is keeping us out.
分隔我們
So let us now, promise within our heart
讓我們現在心裡作出承諾
that this has to go into our heart,
這必須進入我們的心
a very deep feeling for ourselves,
一種很深的感覺
that by God's grace we are born at such a juncture
就是透過神的恩典 我們在這些 事情發生的轉接點出生
that we are the people who are beneficiaries
我們是得到神的祝福的受益人
of the blessings of God that we have got our Realization,
我們得到自覺
that we have risen so high.
已經升得很高
But now let us spread our wings, but we are cutting them down.
現在就讓我們伸展我們雙翼 我 們卻剪斷它
Don't become small-minded people,
不要成為心胸狹小的人
worried about small, small things here and there.
只擔憂各種細微鎖碎的事情
Nothing is important.
沒什麽是重要的
If you see in your previous lives, you have had all kinds of foods,
若你看看你過往的生命 你擁有 各種食物
you have had all kinds of trips,
各種旅程
you have done every kind of marriages, you have done every kind of
經歷各種婚姻 做過各種
other nonsensical thing that people waste time with.
荒唐的事情 人們浪費自己的 時間
It's over now, finished. Now you do something new.
現在這些全都過去 完結了。 現在你要做一些新事
How many people you have married in previous lives
你過往的生命曾與多少人結婚
and how many houses you had in previous lives
擁有過多少房子
and how many pleasures you have had,
有過多少歡愉
finished now - finish it.
現在全都完結了 結束它
This is a special time, the best time of Ritambhara
這是特別的時刻 讓你成長最佳 的Ritambhara時刻
where you have to grow. That's the point is, the season is that.
這是重點 這就是季節
In this season if you do not grow,
在這季節裡 若你不成長
you won't grow.
就不會成長
You have to take full advantage.
你要好好充分利用它
With full intensity
完全的熱切
you have to do Sahaja Yoga.
做霎哈嘉瑜伽的工作
That doesn't mean that you give up your jobs, or anything.
這不是說你要放棄你的工作 放 棄什麽
If you are intense in Sahaja Yoga, you will be intense in everything.
若你對霎哈嘉瑜伽熱誠 就會對 一切都熱誠
But there is no intensity.
但這裡卻沒有這份熱誠
Munich I decided just,
我剛決定 慕尼黑
I don't know if Warren has told you - Munich
我不知道華倫有否告訴你 慕尼黑
"You didn't tell them about Munich?"
你沒有告訴他們有關慕尼黑
All right - Munich. I decided last minute,
好吧 慕尼黑 我在最後一刻 決定
because there was a horrid one
因為有個來自慕尼黑
who had come from Munich and had told Me
可怕的傢伙告訴我
that Munich's seekers will ask such questions.
慕尼黑的求道者會問這種問題
I didn't like them at all. She was very arrogant.
我完全不喜歡他們 她很傲慢
I said I am not going to Munich.
我說我不會去慕尼黑
But in Vienna I just felt the vibrations of Munich.
但在維也納 我卻感覺到慕尼黑 的生命能量
And I was amazed. I said, "All right, I am going to Munich."
我很驚訝 我說 好吧 我會去 慕尼黑
We had to run up and down to get My visa,
他們跑上跑下為我拿簽證
this thing. Everything worked out, as usual.
辦這事 一切如常的成就了
And in that short time, three days,
在短時間內 三天
four hundred people were there.
有四百人在哪裡
And so intense, I tell you, so intense, even children, so intense,
那麽熱誠 我告訴你 那麽熱誠 即使孩子也很熱誠
and they were listening to every word I was saying,
他們聽我說的每一個字
and picking up as pearls,
就像撿到珍珠那樣
precious as diamonds,
珍貴如鑽石
every word they were noting it down.
他們把每個字都記下來
And when they had their Realization they were just stunned people.
當他們得到自覺 他們都是很 奇妙的人
Imagine the Germans, coming over you people, English.
試想像德國人 超越你們 英國人
What will happen to you?
什麽會發生在你身上
They are people of determination.
他們很有決心
If they decide to do good, they'll do lot of good.
若他們決定做好事 就會做很多 好事
They are not like this.
他們不像這裡的人
And then when I left them,
當我離開他們
for one hour they were in the hall, just stunned,
離開一小時 他們在會堂裡 十 分令人喜悅
discussing about Sahaja Yoga.
在討論霎哈嘉瑜伽
But here as soon as I go away,
但在這裡 一旦我離開
people start discussing something so nonsensical.
人們開始討論一些荒謬的事情
I hear it. I know the vibrations and everything.
我聽到 我知道生命能量 我 知道一切
We are not intense, we must increase our intensity.
我們並不熱誠 我們必需增加我們的熱誠度
That is what is called as Shraddha.
這是被稱為堅信Shraddha
Is important, very important.
這很重要 很重要
And I am sure this year you will make it a point
我肯定今年你們要特別注重
to do intense understanding of Sahaja Yoga.
要對霎哈嘉瑜伽有更熱切的理解
That intensity is lacking.
你們仍然缺少了這份熱誠
May be there is something gone wrong with you in the past
或許你的過去有些不妥
and you are conditioned about it, or you think about it.
因此你有些制約 或你想著它
How can I do it, it is too much.
我怎能做到呢 這樣太多了
You can do it, everything, you forget the past, forget the past.
你能做到 做到一切 你忘記 過去 忘記過去
Past has no meaning whatsoever in Sahaja Yoga.
在霎哈嘉瑜伽 不管如何 過去 都是毫無意義
You are being completely renovated
你已經完全得到修復
but just use your mechanism.
只要運用你的機制
I have worked so hard with you people
我已經很辛勤的與你們一起工作
that nothing wrong with your mechanism.
你們的機制並沒出問題
Only thing you have no faith in yourself.
唯一是你們對自己沒有信心
And those who do not have faith in themselves
對自己沒有信心的人
are always bumptious people.
常常是自負自大的人
So first of all station yourself within your Spirit,
所以你先要紮根在你內在的靈裡
within your heart and try to develop your powers,
內在的心裡 嘗試發展你的力量
inner powers, not of talking and showing off,
內在的力量 不是談話或炫耀的 力量
but inner powers.
而是內在的力量
Still so many are possessed, you know that.
你們仍有很多人被鬼附 你們是知道的
It's a shameful thing
這是羞恥的事
that even now in the temple of God there are people
即使現在 在神的聖殿裡
who are possessed by horrible evil things.
仍有人被可怕的邪魔附體
How can it be?
怎會這樣
You are the carrier of all these, even now, how can it be?
即使至現在 你仍是這些邪魔的 載體 怎會這樣呢
So one has to be very intensely there,
所以我們要非常熱切的在那裡
and those today who are looking to be nothing,
今天那些對自己沒什麽期望的人
will grow into something so great,
會成長為很偉大的人
that you will be amazed at yourself.
連你也詫異自己的成就
"How is it I have become so great?"
我怎能變得如此偉大呢
But the first and foremost thing is disciplining.
但首先和最重要的是紀律
Discipline yourself.
好好管束自己
When it comes to eating, some people eat too much.
當進食時 有些人吃得太多
When it comes to talking, some people talk too much.
當談話時 有些人說得太多
Or they do not talk at all, or they eat not at all.
或有些人 他們完全不說話 或 不進食
All this is indiscipline.
這全是違反紀律
But going higher to this spiritual life,
要進入這個更高的靈性生命
best thing is to take the discipline from your Spirit
最好是遵守來自你的靈的紀律
and you are disciplined automatically.
你自動會律己
Let the Spirit rule you.
讓靈掌管你
It's possible. It's possible,
這是有可能發生的
because I have seen in such a short time
因為我曾見過 在這樣短時間內
and when I have been there for such a short time,
我在那裡很短時間
I don't even know their names.
甚至不知道他們的名字
Here practically I know all of you,
在這裡 我差不多認識你們 全部人
by your names, and by your vibrations also.
知道你們的名字 也知道你們的 生命能量
And they have gone up so much.
他們昇進得那麽多
So, today is a great day.
今天是偉大的日子
Of course a great privilege.
當然是極大的特權
Always you are privileged people, like House of Lords.
你們常常都是擁有特權的人 像 上議院(貴族院)
Is true, but may be,
這是事實 但或許
one day may come when this House of Lords may be banished completely.
有天這個上議院會完全被廢除
You have to behave like lords.
你們的言行要像貴族
That is why My humble request is
我謙卑的請求
that you must learn
你們必須學習
to worship discipline.
敬拜紀律
I don't say, "Do this, do that."
我不會說 做這事 做那事
You know what is to be done.
你知道該做什麽
And then on top of that, you should not tell Me,
除此之外 你不應告訴我
"I know, I should have, I know."
我知道 我本來應該 我知道
When you know, why don't you do it? You are empowered.
你既然知道 為何還不做 你已經獲授權
Today let us, with full confidence in ourselves
今天讓我們對自己充滿信心
and in our ascent,
在昇進裡
let us with full intensity attend this Puja
讓我們充滿熱誠的參加這個崇拜
and in our hearts decide
在我們心裡決定
that, "I am going to discipline myself."
我要好好管束自己
May God bless you.
願神祝福你們
Navaratri is beginning with a big force.
女神拉特利節以很大的力量開始
But vibration-wise is good,
生命能量很好
Vibrations are very strong today.
今天生命能量很強
Tremendous.
很巨大
And you take full advantage of them.
你要充分利用它
If you want, you can use your left hand or right hand,
若你想 你可以運用左手或右手
whichever way you like.
以任何你喜歡的方式來做
and right hand on the earth. Or, left hand...
右手放在大地。或左手
I would say it is left hand, mostly.
我會說是用左手 大部分人
Even those who look egoistical are
即使是那些看似自我的人
under the power of some sort of a possession.
他們受某種邪魔附體力量的影響
And they are even worse than people who are really egoistical
他們比真正自我的人更惡劣
because they are themselves not aware at all
因為他們完全不知道
what they are talking about.
自己在說些什麽